Doll & Richards Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Notes and Research Files, 1880s-1978, bulk 1930s-1960s, Series 2:; (Boxes 15-16, 78; 1.2 linear feet)
  - Healy, G.P.A., 1947 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Hills, Laura Coombs, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Homer, Winslow, 1883-1949 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Homer, Winslow - The Life and Works of Winslow Homer, by William Howe Downes [Property of Wendell Zoehler], 1911-1960s (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Arthur C., 1951-1953 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Macknight, Dodge, 1888-1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Nanteuil, [Robert], circa 1890s-1920s (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Notecards on Provenance of Paintings, circa before 1942 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Reported Sales of Paintings by Others, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1878-1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - O'Hara, Eliot, circa 1930s-1970 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Piranesi, [Giovanni Battista], circa 1890s-1920s (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Rembrandt, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Rowland, Benjamin, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Rubens, 1946-1954 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Joseph Lindon, circa 1948-1950 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Vidal, Margarita Hahn, 1963-circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Young-Hunter, John, 1940-1956 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - United States Presidential Administrations, circa 1900s (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "William Morris Hunt, Artist," by Helen M. Knowlton, circa 1913 (Box 78 (sol), Folder 1)
- Business Records, circa 1866-1978, bulk 1910s-1960s, Series 3:; (Boxes 16-18; 1.9 linear feet)
  Business records include minutes of meetings and other general records pertaining to the day-to-day gallery operations, such as contacts cards and mailing lists, framing and matting information, labels, exhibition records, and miscellaneous lists and notes about customers and artwork. A detailed description of the gallery's operations by Wendell Zoehler is also found here.
  Six shoeboxes of index cards record contacts primarily of customers, but also artists, consignors, and businesses. Cards typically include first and last name, address, dates of contact and the initials of the Doll & Richards employee, a code in the upper right-hand corner, and notes such as occupation or date of death. For customers, the artist's name, description of artwork, date, and price of paintings bought is written on the back of the card. Cards appear to be arranged in three groups - current contacts, contacts removed from the file, and contacts which need to be filed or removed. Within these groups, the cards are in loose alphabetical order by last name or business name.
  - 2 Park Street, Boston, MA [Photocopy], 1907 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Address Book, before 1959 - circa 1969 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Azeez Khayat Gallery, circa 1927-1966 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Azeez Khayat Gallery, circa 1949-1962 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Back Labels, circa 1866-1880 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Card File, Contacts, (shoebox) (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Abramson-Zwicker, 1920s-1971
    [Business?], circa 1910s-1960s
  - Card File, Contacts [Removed?], Abare-Draper, 1910s-early 1960s, (shoebox) (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Card File, Contacts [Removed?], Draper-Kyle, 1910s-early 1960s, (shoebox) (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Card File, Contacts [Removed?], Labunski-Rittenhouse, 1910s-early 1960s, (shoebox) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Card File, Contacts [Removed?], Robb-Zug, 1910s-early 1960s, (shoebox) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Card File, Contacts, (shoebox) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Contacts - Hold All, 1960s
    Contacts - Hold for Mr. Goldberg, 1910s-1960s
    Contacts - Unlabeled, 1910s-1960s
  - Card File, Sales by Artist's Name, circa 1930s-1960s, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - Clients' Artwork Purchases Register, 1924-1957 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Cost Estimates and Appraisals, circa 1924-1940 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Exhibitions, Ancient Egyptian Jewelry (June 1953), 1953 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Exhibitions, "Old Time Itinerant Artists" (Jan 23-Feb 3, 1940), 1938, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Exhibitions Lists, 1945-1950 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Guest Register, 1963-1969 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Histories of Doll & Richards, circa 1966-1978 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - List of Subscribers to Arundel Society Publications, 1885-1897, (Book) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Mailing Lists, circa 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Mat Board Sizes, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors Meetings, 1941-1942 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, 1943-1945 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, 1945-1950 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, 1950-1956 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and Stockholders Meetings, 1956-1961 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Lists and Notes, circa 1880s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Lists and Notes, circa 1880s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notebook Listing Clients' Artwork for Sale (1946-1961) and Exhibitions (1941-1963), circa 1890s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Legal Records, 1863-1906, 1941-1962, Series 4:; (Boxes 18, 78; 0.3 linear feet)
  Legal Records contains contracts, agreements, certificates of stock, certificates of copyrights, and founding documents.
  - Agreement for $2500 loan to Chas. E. Hendrickson [Photocopy], 1781 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Agreements Between George and Joseph Inness, and Doll & Richards, 1875-1877 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Articles of Agreement [Photocopy], 1866 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Articles of Copartnership [Photocopy], 1870 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Articles of Organization, 1941, June 13 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Certificates of Copyright, 1863-1906 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Contracts Regarding "Abraham Lincoln at the Consecration of the National Cemetery at Gettysburg, Pennsylvania," 1879 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Corporate Officers, 1962, March-April (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Daniel Webster Engraving, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "The Future" Copyright, 1868-1869 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Doll & Richards Stock Certificate Book, 1941-1962 (Box 78 (sol), Folder 2)
- Financial Records, 1871-1973, bulk 1902-1969, Series 5:; (Boxes 18-69, 79, BV81-112; 55 linear feet)
  Financial records provide an extensive and rich source of gallery sales and other transactions. Financial records prior to 1902 are limited; however, from 1902 through the 1960s, the records are comprehensive and frequently cross-referenced. The records provide multiple access points via date, customer or consignor name, artist name, and sales and work form number.
  The series is arranged as two subseries:
  5.1: Gallery Records, 1871-1969
  5.2: Sales Records, circa 1883, 1901-1973, bulk 1902-1968
  - Gallery Records, 1871-1969, 5.1:
    The financial records of the gallery include accounts receivable and payable ledgers, voluminous card files for accounts, account ledgers, cashbooks, checkstubs, daybooks, journals, price lists, and other financial ledgers.
    Records of accounts with customers, consignors, artists, merchants, galleries, museums, and others are housed in oversized ledgers from 1902-1911 and on card files from 1911-1968, providing comprehensive documentation of the gallery's transactions and access points to information based on names. Each ledger includes an index, and entries include cross-references to daybooks, journals, and cash books. Each card includes the account name and address; dates and amounts of transactions; balance on the account; cross-references to the page in the daybook, journal, or cash book in which the entry was made; and occasionally notes about the account. Cards are arranged in alphabetical order by the account name. Additional subject cards such as "advertising," "restoration," and "private books" are arranged at the end of the card file; some subject cards are also filed alphabetically with the account cards. Also filed at the end of the card file are cards for accounts which were active or unresolved, or which needed to be filed.
    Cash books (labeled "A"-"Q") record daily credits and debits. Each entry includes the date, details of the transaction, and costs incurred for merchandise, manufacturing, labor, etc. Older entries (1902-1911) reference the page in which the account was recorded in the oversized account ledgers.
    Daybooks (labeled "DBA"-"DBT") record individual transactions from 1902-1966, and include details such as the date, buyer or merchant name, cost of purchase or sale price, and the cost of supplies or gallery expenses. Each entry also includes the sales and work order form numbers for cross-reference; in the older daybooks (1902-1911) the page in which the account is recorded in the oversized account ledgers is also included. All transactions on each page are totaled and balanced.
    Invoice and Sales Accounts books (1871-1967) list drawings, etchings, photographs, bronzes, furniture, watercolors, prints, lithographs, paintings, and other works of art, often in lots, on consignment from various owners. Many entries include details of the disposition of the work of art. The entries are arranged by sale lot number and, since these were assigned in order of occurrence, the entries are also chronological. However, some earlier sale lot numbers are repeated at the beginning of later books.
    Journals (labeled "A"-"P") record the gallery's transactions for services such as gilding or joining, frame supplies, restoration of paintings, sales of works of art, purchases of prints, shipping, salaries, utilities, office supplies, etc. The front and back covers of the ledger books were removed for preservation.
    Price lists are typically typed or written on exhibition catalogs; occasionally the price list also includes a name, presumably of the buyer. Additional price lists and notes on prices of artwork are scattered within Series 1, Series 3, Series 7, and Series 8.
    - Accounts Receivable and Payable Ledger, 1921-1941 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Accounts Receivable and Payable Ledger, 1941, July - 1948, July (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Accounts Receivable and Payable Ledger, 1948, July - 1957, January (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Accounts Receivable and Payable Ledger, 1957, February - 1967, September, (2 volumes) (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Card File, Accounts (Box 18)
      - Abare-Bartlett, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Bartlett-Brettell, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Card File, Accounts (Box 19)
      - Brewer-Cheever, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Chemists Club-Cutting, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Dabney-Elevator, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Elfers-Fusele, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Card File, Accounts (Box 20)
      - Gable-Hamlin, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Hammell-Howard, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Howe-Kew Gallery, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Keyes-Lytton, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Card File, Accounts (Box 21)
      - MacAusland-Mitton, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Mixter-Otis, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Ott-Potki, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Potter-Sachs, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Card File, Accounts (Box 22)
      - Sachse-Sherburne, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Sherer-Sturgis, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Sturtevant-Wadsworth, 1907-1967, (shoebox) (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Wagner-Wilson, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Card File, Accounts and Subjects, 1911-1967, (shoebox) (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Wiltse-Zwicker
      Appraisal-Manufacturing
    - Card File, Subjects, 1911-1968, (shoebox) (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Manufacturing-Unlabeled
      Accounts Active in 1968
      Inactive Accounts
    - Card File, Subjects, 1911-1968, (shoebox) (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Accounts Payable, Consignments
      Accounts Receivable Completed
      Card Out
      General Ledger
    - Cash Book [Q], 1967-1969 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Check Stubs (Box 24)
      - Nos. 19,448-19,467 (Book 30), June 30 - July 16, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Nos. 19,468-19,967 (Book 31), July 16, 1941 - July 9, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Nos. 19,968-20,464 (Book 32), November 24, 1942 - February 15, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Nos. 20,465-20,964 (Book 33), February 16, 1944 - March 21, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Nos. 20,965-21,464 (Book 34), March 22, 1945 - April 16, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Nos. 21,465-21,964 (Book 35), April 17, 1946 - May 6, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Nos. 21,965-22,461 (Book 36), May 6, 1947 - May 19, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Nos. 22,462-22,961 (Book 37), May 20, 1948 - June 6, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Nos. 22,962-23,462 (Book 38), June 6, 1949 - June 19, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Nos. 23,463-23,963 (Book 39), June 19, 1950 - September 11, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Nos. 23,964-24,464 (Book 40), September 11, 1951 - November 7, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Check Stubs (Box 25)
      - Nos. 24,465-24,965 (Book 41), November 7, 1952 - December 31, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 24,966-25,466 (Book 42), December 31, 1953 - March 28, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Nos. 25,467-25,967 (Book 43), March 29, 1955 - July 5, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Nos. 25,968-26,468 (Book 44), July 5, 1956 - October 11, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Nos. 1,501-1,992, 1963, February - 1965, March (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Consignment Invoices, Ken Gore, 1964-1967 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Daybook [DBN], December 31, 1926 - August 31, 1931, (4 folders) (Box 25, Folder 7-10)
    - Daybook (DBO), 1931, September - 1938, November, (4 folders) (Box 25, Folder 11-14)
    - Daybook (DBP), 1938, November - 1945, May (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Daybook (DBP), 1938, November - 1945, May, (3 folders) (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
    - Daybook (DBQ), 1945, May - 1950, April, (4 folders) (Box 26, Folder 4-7)
    - Daybook (DBR), 1950, April - 1955, April, (5 folders) (Box 26, Folder 8-12)
    - Daybook [DBS], 1955, April - 1960, December, (4 folders) (Box 26, Folder 13-16)
    - Daybook (DBT), 1961, January - 1966, May, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 17-18)
    - Daybook (DBT), 1961, January - 1966, May (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Financial Ledger, 1957, September - 1963, February (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Financial Ledger, 1963, February - 1970, March (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Invoice and Account Sales Book [Consignments] (Box 27)
      - Sales 1-177, 1871-1877 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Sales 178-360, 1877-1881 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Sales 361-538, 1881-1891 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Sales 539-616, 1891-1901 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Sales 617-691, 1898-1902 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Sales 692-810, 1902-1909 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Sales 811-992, 1909-1917 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Invoice and Account Sales Book [Consignments] (Box 28)
      - Sales 993-1176, 1917-1955 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Sales 1177-1504, 1928-1967 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Invoices, "F," 1934-1952 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Invoices, "H," 1890, 1933-1954 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Journal [A], May 1, 1902 - April 30, 1904 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Journal [B], April 30, 1904 - April 30, 1906 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Journal [C], April 30, 1906 - August 24, 1908 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Journal [D], August 31, 1908 - June 30, 1911 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Journal [E], July 1, 1911 - May 15, 1914 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Journal [F], May 29, 1914 - January 18, 1917 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Journal [G], January 18, 1917 - December 9, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Journal [H], December 16, 1919 - August 27, 1923 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Journal [I], September 1, 1923 - June 30, 1927 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Journal [J], July 1, 1927 - August 29, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Journal [K], September 2, 1930 - October 25, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Journal [L], October 31, 1934 - June 30, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Journal [M], July 1, 1938 - June 30, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Journal [N], July 1, 1941 - January 24, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Journal [O], January 26, 1950 - December 6, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Journal [P], December 6, 1963 - October 16, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Price Lists, 1923-1929 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Price Lists, 1930-1932 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Price Lists, 1933-1935, (3 folders) (Box 29, Folder 10-12)
    - Price Lists, Laura Coombs Hills, 1935-1940 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Price Lists, 1936-1939, (4 folders) (Box 29, Folder 14-17)
    - Price Lists, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Price Lists, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Price Lists, [Season 1941-1942], 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Price Lists, 1942-1944, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 21-22)
    - Price Lists, [Season 1945-1946], 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Price Lists, 1945-1948, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 24-25)
    - Price Lists, Season 1948-1949, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Price Lists, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Price Lists, Season 1951-1952, 1914, 1951-1952, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Price Lists, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
    - Price Lists, Season 1953-1954, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Price Lists, 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Price Lists, Season 1954-1955, 1954-1955, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Price Lists, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Price Lists, circa 1956-1962 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Price Lists, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Price Lists, Season 1957-1958, 1957-1958 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Price Lists, Season 1958-1959, 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Price Lists, Season 1959-1960, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Price Lists, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Receipts and Expenses Ledger, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Reconciled Checks, November 28, 1955 - January 4, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Reconciled Checks, January 25 - March 2, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Accounts Ledger, 1902, May - 1906, April (Box BV81)
    - Accounts Ledger, 1906, May - 1911, April (Box BV82)
    - Cash Book A, 1902, May - 1904, January (Box BV83)
    - Cash Book B, 1904, January - 1905, December (Box BV84)
    - Cash Book C, 1905, December - 1908, January (Box BV85)
    - Cash Book D, 1908, February - 1910, May (Box BV86)
    - Cash Book E, 1910, May - 1912, November (Box BV87)
    - Cash Book F, 1912, November - 1915, May (Box BV88)
    - Cash Book G, 1915, May - 1917, November (Box BV89)
    - Cash Book H, 1917, December - 1920, November (Box BV90)
    - Cash Book I, 1920, November - 1923, November (Box BV91)
    - Cash Book J, 1923, November - 1926, October (Box BV92)
    - Cash Book [K], 1926, October - 1929, May (Box BV93)
    - Cash Book [L], 1929, May - 1933, June (Box BV94)
    - Cash Book [M], 1933, June - 1941, April (Box BV95)
    - Cash Book [N], 1941, April - 1950, March (Box BV96)
    - Cash Book [O], 1950, April - 1961, January (Box BV97)
    - Cash Book [P], 1964, December - 1969 (Box BV98)
    - Daybook [DBA], May 1, 1902 - September 30, 1903 (Box BV99)
    - Daybook (DBB), October 1, 1903 - February 21, 1905 (Box BV100)
    - Daybook (DBC), February 24, 1905 - November 20, 1906 (Box BV101)
    - Daybook (DBD), November 20, 1906 - December 8, 1908 (Box BV102)
    - Daybook (DBE), December 11, 1908 - March 31, 1911 (Box BV103)
    - Daybook (DBF), April 1, 1911 - November 29, 1913 (Box BV104)
    - Daybook [DBG], December 1, 1913 - May 23, 1916 (Box BV105)
    - Daybook [DBH], May 25, 1916 - December 24, 1918 (Box BV106)
    - Daybook [DBI], December 31, 1918 - February 10, 1921 (Box BV107)
    - Daybook [DBJ], February 18, 1921 - June 9, 1922 (Box BV108)
    - Daybook [DBK], June 12, 1922 - January 8, 1924 (Box BV109)
    - Daybook (DBL), January 12, 1924 - September 4, 1925 (Box BV110)
    - Daybook [DBM], September 11, 1925 - December 31, 1926 (Box BV111)
    - Trial Balance Book, 1941, July - 1967, September (Box BV112)
  - Sales Records, circa 1883, 1901-1973, bulk 1902-1968, 5.2:
    Found are sales and consignment invoices, letterpress copybooks for consignment account statements, and voluminous sales and work order forms. The sales and work order forms were filled out when sales were made or orders were taken for work such as framing, restoration, and shipping. The sales and work order forms typically include the buyer's name and address, date, form number, price, and details such as the cross-section of the frame or notations such as "DBN 21," indicating the sale was recorded in Daybook N, page 21. Each form is numbered and many bear a letter prefix. According to Wendell Zoehler, the letter "A" indicates sales by Fergus Turner; "C," Arthur McKean; and "D," Wendell Zoeller. The letter "B" is for sales of paintings and watercolors. Those represented by the letters "L," "LE," "S" are unknown. Sales by Lucius B. Peck are also represented by a letter, but it is unknown which one.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject. Sales and work order forms are grouped by the letter prior to the form number and filed alphabetically; forms without a letter prior to the form number are filed first. Within each group, forms are arranged in numerical order based on the form number, which corresponds loosely to chronological order. Other sales forms for Helen Plowden/William Stanley Haseltine were removed from their original location and collocated into five boxes, presumably by the gallery. The order for these forms has been retained and are filed at the end of the subseries.
    - Consignment Account Statements, Letterpress Copybook #6, June 3, 1936 - January 18, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Sales and Consignment Invoices, circa 1883, 1901, 1919-1972, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 21-22)
    - Sales and Consignment Invoices, Fine Art Society (London), 1937-1945 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Sales and Work Order Forms (Box 30)
      - Nos. 45,000-45,099, April 5 - May 16, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Nos. 45,100-45,199, May 16 - June 9, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - Nos. 45,200-45,299, June 10 - August 25, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - Nos. 45,300-45,399, August 25 - October 7, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - Nos. 45,400-45,499, October 8 - November 8, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - Nos. 45,500-45,599, November 8 - December 10, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - Nos. 45,600-45,699, December 10-19, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - Nos. 45,700-45,799, December 19-24, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - Nos. 45,800-45,899, December 24, 1902 - February 19, 1903 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Sales and Work Order Forms (Box 31)
      - Nos. 45,900-45,999, February 24 - April 11, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 46,000-46,099, April 11 - May 28, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Nos. 46,100-46,199, May 29 - June 29, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Nos. 46,200-46,299, June 29 - September 2, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Nos. 46,300-46,399, September 2 - October 6, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Nos. 46,400-46,499, October 6 - November 3, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Nos. 46,500-46,599, November 4 - December 1, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Nos. 46,600-46,699, December 2-15, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Nos. 46,700-46,799, December 15-22, 1903 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Nos. 46,800-46,899, December 22, 1903 - January 18, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Nos. 46,900-46,999, January 18 - March 1, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Nos. 47,000-47,099, March 2 - April 16, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Nos. 47,100-47,199, April 18 - May 31, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Nos. 47,200-47,299, May 31 - July 25, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Nos. 47,300-47,399, July 28 - October 1, 1904 (Box 31, Folder 15)